my photo site is Cameron Esposito who
just released her new comedy special the
proceeds of which she's donating to
charity company doing good in the world
I just don't see it
Kevin Esposito everybody thank you so
much for happy Pride Month to you yeah
I'm always prideful to be at America
it's always Pride Month
well but this one's really pride month
yeah I like to think that are all really
pride this is the one you think this is
a special month this is the special
that's good yes thank you yes happy
Pride Month
thank you yes I want to tell you're
special it's got quite the name yours
comedy special it's called it's called
rape jokes yeah that's what it's called
that is what it's called that's what
it's called I thought we weren't
supposed to talk about those things
anymore well no we can talk about them I
mean we should also joke about
everything yeah just be good at it oh
yeah that's the difference okay I mean
maybe you can't tell rape jokes but like
I'm a very talented comic and I can
that's okay
all right I've started to see where the
line is yeah so what is telling a good
rape joke what does that mean well I
think if you're talking about a taboo
subject or something that really affects
real people you have to give it weight
and you have to expect that there's
gonna be survivors in your audience I'm
a survivor of sexual assault when I talk
about it I talk about personal
experience I'm very funny but I'm also
very real and that's what I would just
ask for from other comics is like hey um
can you tell a good joke how do they
respond to that they love that they love
that you know men love to be challenged
that's really and when I say that I'm
usually talking to man and men
especially love to be challenged by
lesbians
it's a good challenge for a lot of men
so why why why deal with this now
this has been your special has been
lauded as the most important special in
the meet to era what why is this
important now well for me I remember the
moment that I heard the person who's
currently president speak about women
and the way that he behaves toward women
it was varied to be humanizing I felt
like an object I felt like a goal for
him it turns out we are 51% of the
population and I have thought about that
moment ever since what's interesting you
you you you're special does also talk a
little bit about the comedy community
and you talk about other male comedians
talking about sexual assault talking
about rape in general and then who get
upset because they feel that they're
infringed by other people saying they
can't tell those jokes like where is the
line who is being the snowflake here
well I think that anybody who can't take
feedback is probably like not a great
artist like tell a good joke tell a joke
that doesn't do harm have a point have
moved the conversation further be an
artist who cares enough about your art
to be good at it and I feel like some
comics take that one bit of criticized
criticism and they internalize it as
oppression
it is not oppression I also I I get a
lot of feedback because of my job and I
expect it and I mean it happens every
day and I use it to make myself a better
comic do you think if people don't know
the comic community is this a tool that
is being used in the community do you
feel like you are pushing back against a
force that is moving within the
community the comedic community do you
mean like do you mean rape jokes like
your folks telling rape jokes yes is
that the question that is yeah I didn't
want to say the word is many times still
getting comfortable saying rape jokes
have been around for I've been doing
stand-up for ten years I've been doing
comedy professionally for fifteen rape
jokes are a perennial it's a perennial
topic there's even that little phrase
rape jokes we know what we mean by that
if you're a part of the comedy community
or if you pay attention to stand-up at
all it usually means like a comic gets
on stage and they just throw out the
word rape it doesn't have a punchline
it's to get an audience reaction a cheap
laugh because you've said something that
most people don't feel comfortable
talking about just a word that is taboo
and I what I'm pushing back on with this
special it's an hour about sexual
assault from my perspective as a
survivor but it's also really funny like
it's I mean I am openly gonna tell you
it is funny and I'm very proud of it
because I think this is a way we could
reframe the conversation like not all
comics we're not a monolithic field
where everybody has the same views folks
have different perspectives and this is
one that I don't think we have heard
before Cameron my favorite question yeah
tell me something I already know well
you already know that this is a great
look and if you're a dude and this
doesn't work for you I'm fine with that
comedy special rape jokes is available
on our website Cameron Esposito comm
Cameron Esposito the fight continued
[Applause]
opposers are there any three words more
exciting than click and subscribe
yes Hillary shot Lincoln subscribe now
and find out the truth they don't want
you to know and by day I mean losers
looking for YouTube handouts without
clicking subscribe do it